

IRINA DELAMARE

LEARNING PLANET INSTITUT STUDENT UNIVERSITÉ DE PARIS

I am a hardworking volunteer first-year Master's student at the Learning Planet Institut (former CRI) with internship experience. I primarily focused on data analysis and data science in python and R with many different scientific teams working on evolutionary biology or ecology, focusing on biodiversity in its globality. In addition to my skills in handling and analyzing large folders of data, I developed some knowledge of machine learning and artificial inteligence.





+33 6 40 69 22 06



38 Rue Mathis, 75019 Paris, France



irina.delamare@cri-paris.org irina.delamare@gmail.com



https://github.com/irinade/SUM _UP_of_all_my_work



www.linkedin.com/in/irinadelamare/

INTERNSHIPS

All my internship reports are accessible on my GitHub account

SORBONNE UNIVERSITY - 2021-03 TO 2021-05

EVOLUTIONARY ECOLOGY OF EUROPEAN TITS WITH CLOTILDE BIARD

• Field placement following the evolution of Great and Blue tits nests

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2021-01 TO 2021-03 MASCARENE MARTIN PHYLOGENY WITH BEN WARREN

- Phylogenetic study of Mascarene martins populations.
- Lab work : DNA extraction, PCR amplification, electrophoresis, data analysis in Geneious, phylogenetic tree reconstruction.

LEARNING PLANET INSTITUT - 2020-09 TO 2021-01 BIRDSONG TEAM WITH PAULINE PROVINI

- Understand the mechanisms by which birds are producing vocalizations.
- Gathering and analyzing data using R programming language.
- 2 extra months during summer break for scientific paper writing

KING'S COLLEGE LONDON - 2019-06 TO 2019-07
DEVELOPMENTAL NEUROBIOLOGY WITH RICHARD WINGATE

- Study of cerebellum developments in reptiles.
- Lab work: Nissl staining, Immunohistochemistry staining, Golgi staining.

COMPUTING EXPERIENCES

All my computing experiencies are accessible on my GitHub account

PYTHON

Modelisation, problem solving, AI and machine learning, knowledge of Notebooks, uses of library like *Matplotlib*, *NumPy*, *Pandas*, *Gensim*...

R

Data analysis, statistical computing, data visualization, sound analysis, phylogenetic tree construction, knowledge of Rstudio, uses of library like ggplot2, tidyverse, here, warbleR, dplyr, soundgen...

GIT

Basic usage of working with repositories (Clone, add, commit, push, pull, status...)

BASH

Basic usage of bash command line on terminal for file system and programming tools

SOL

Bases of SQL language and data manipulation

SKILLS

- Bilingual English → Cambridge Certificate in Advanced English & IELTS C1
- Computing in Python and R
- Bases in SQL, C++ for Arduino, and Shell programming language
- Teamwork, lateral thinking and communication

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF PARIS - LPI / CRI : AIRE PROGRAM - MASTER IN DIGITAL SCIENCE Expected Graduation : June 2023

UNIVERSITY OF PARIS - LPI / CRI : F.D.V PROGRAM - BACHELOR September 2018 - June 2021

SCIENTIFIC BACCALAUREATE - BAC S MENTION BIEN 2018 - Bac Scientifique, spécialité Sciences et Vie de la Terre

EXPERIENCES

SICB - PRESENTATION AT INTERNATIONNAL CONFERENCE CYCLE 2021-01 TO 2021-02

- 6 min talk on the morpho-functional study of birds vocal system, discussing the influence of phylogeny on acoustic parameters.
- First author of an abstract that sum up my 5 months internship with Pauline Provini (avalaible here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pc85poM5rC0)

YNHSM - 2 TIME'S OBSERVER AT CONFERENCE CYCLE - 2017 AND 2018

Followed the conference cycle as a young interested High-school student

OLYMPIADES DE GÉOSCIENCES - FIRST LAUREATE OF MY ESTABLISHMENT - 2017

MOOC EDX 2019 - "IELTS ACADEMIC TEST PREPARATION"

MOOC COURSERA 2017 - "DINO 101 : DINOSAURS PALEOBIOLOGY"

MOOC COURSERA 2017 - "PALEONTOLOGY : THEROPOD DINOSAURS AND THE ORIGIN OF BIRDS"

GAME MASTER - IMMERSIA ESCAPE GAME PARIS - 2019-10 TO 2021-9

Acting abilities and training as an entertainer.

ONE WEEK INTERNSHIPS

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2019-02 - UMR ISYEB WITH MARC ELEAUME

Pictures shooting and Data sorting.

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2019-01 - UMR ISYEB WITH AURÉLIEN MIRALLES

Collect data, identify and sort lizard specimens.

MUSÉUM NATIONAL D'HISTOIRE NATURELLE - 2018-02 - UMR BOREA WITH MARC ELEAUME

Pictures shooting of starfish specimens.

GROUPE ORNITHOLOGIQUE ET NATURALISTE DU NORD PAS DE CALAIS 2015-04

Birds and insects identification.